Now I get it.
This is that big-mouthed
monster's natural habitat.
The death knell it let out was a lure
to draw a huge horde here.
The pandemonium is enough to terrify
even what lives in this monstrous land.
Sir Tooka...
We still have some time before they arrive.
There's... There's an
outrageous number of them.
Knowing that is enough.
Everyone, listen to me.
I'll act as bait and draw the monsters to me.
Use the time I buy to get to the witch.
I'll create an opportunity for you all
to escape, no matter what.
Big Sis!
Lis.
My own carelessness brought this on us.
I must be the one to take action.
As you know, my senses are quite sharp.
I'm also an expert at maneuvering
in terrain like this.
Big Sis...
Lis, make sure you listen
to Tooka and Seras until I return.
- Lis, make sure you listen
- All right.
If you're that insistent,
I'll let you lure them away.
But on one condition.
You have to promise us
that you'll make it back alive.
- Yes, you have my word.
- Did you think I'd agree just like that?
Tooka?
TO THE LIMIT, AND BEYOND
- Eve, your odds of survival are too low.
But I...
First of all, you don't
need to feel responsible.
The monster you cut down
kept hidden until it was
within extremely close range,
then broke concealment without warning.
It would have been a challenge
for you to sense it ahead of time.
Still!
Had I been the one standing where you were,
I would have done the same thing.
I should've used my status
ailment skill immediately.
So this is on me, too.
No reason for you to take all the blame.
But Tooka—
Listen.
Eve Speed, you're indispensable
in getting us to the witch.
She bestowed your kind with that map.
Bringing someone she's entrusted it to
will make our negotiations much easier.
My voice projection gem...
It isn't fully hardened yet,
but it is solid now.
I just hope it functions.
I'm the one with the best chance
at survival given the situation.
Or, to be more accurate,
me, Piggymaru, and Slei.
This team has the best shot at ensuring
we all make it out alive.
Besides, at present,
my status ailment skill is the only thing
guaranteed to deliver lethal damage
to the human-faced beasts.
Responsibility is important,
but I decide where that responsibility
falls within our war band.
So if I say not to worry about it, then don't.
That's an order.
Forgive me.
I can't say I don't like
your strong sense of duty.
Sir Tooka, thank you so much.
It's still too early for thanks.
Save it for after we've all
reached our destination safely.
Yes!
Sir Tooka...
Good luck.
If I don't return, I leave
the rest in your hands.
Yes!
I'd like to ask you not
to say such ominous things,
but for now, I shall simply accept it.
I'm glad you're an
understanding vice captain.
Everyone, run!
Don't get caught in it!
Everyone, hurry up and move!
Suou-san, please lead them!
Okay, got it!
Everyone! This way!
Kanae-san! Everyone, wait!
What's all the uproar about?
What is wrong with these things?!
We're nothing...
but an obstacle to them?
I don't want to die! I don't want to die!
Kanae-san!
Thanks, little pigeon!
It's all right... No one's died yet...
Not a single person...
That's not true.
They're close.
It's almost time, huh?
I ordered Seras and the others to hide
in a cave we found along the way.
That just leaves...
Here we go!
This spot should be good.
You'll be the one to signal the
start of battle, Piggymaru.
Go for it.
Glad you've all got such good hearing.
Taking the bait like damned honest fools...
From here on, it's going
to be a high-speed chase.
No telling if I'll survive this.
Depending on the strength
of those human-faced beasts,
I could be done for.
Still, I can't afford to let my worry show.
Sorry, you two.
Will you put your lives in my hands?
Yeah, you're right.
Let me rephrase.
Will you put your lives
in my hands for their sake?
Assault Accel!
Now...
Let's wage this all-out war!
It can't be...
Yasu-kun.
Oh, it's you, Ayaka?
Hirooka-kun and Sakuma-kun
were part of your group, right?
- Weren't you with them?
- We should be prioritizing the safety
of higher-ranking heroes like me.
We should be prioritizing the safety
We can't afford to have our best talent
taking unnecessary damage here.
So it goes without saying that this was
their fault for being slow to flee.
I-It goes without saying...?
You didn't do anything when the
stampede of monsters appeared?!
What are you trying to say, Ayaka?
Y-You're A-Class!
Yes, and?
Don't you feel a duty to protect
the classmates in your group?!
The students under you are relying on you.
So you need to protect them!
Yasu-kun, you were the only one
there who could have...
Sh-Sh-Sh...
Shut up!
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
Shut your mouth, Ayaka!
Huh?
Wh-What is your problem?!
Why are you still acting like
you're so much better than me?!
Why're you so condescending?!
Where's your sense of hierarchy?!
Face facts already!
Wh-What are you talking about?
There, there, there! That's it, yes!
That's how you always are, Sogou Ayaka!
You aren't even consciously
aware of it most of the time!
You just naturally look down on others!
Hold on!
I was saying you should have protected them—
Not my problem!
I survived because I was strong!
They died because they were weak!
It's as simple as that!
The strong have a responsibility
to shield those without—
There, see?!
Ayaka, you so naturally speak
like you're one of the strong!
That's what I'm talking about!
This noblesse oblige crap!
You always act like a saint
while looking down on others!
Constantly flaunting the difference
between us without intending to be mean!
For starters, both Hirooka and
Sakuma deserved to die anyway!
When shitty, weak, little
Mimori got sent to hell,
they were the first to dog on him!
They constantly made fun
of me behind my back too!
You reap what you sow!
Or what?
Does Miss Class President
who's been blessed from birth
think I should feel sorry for them too?!
You're such a nobody.
Kirihara!
Yasu, do you know what they say
about the measure of a man?
Everyone has an inborn caliber,
and it's only after you make it
that people know if you truly measure up.
If you don't, then your success
will only be temporary.
Are you following me?
What are you trying to say?
You even react like a nobody, Yasu.
Take a hint.
What could I possibly mean other than
that you're drastically beneath me?
You proved you were a nobody
when you forgot your flimsy act
and lost it in front of Sogou.
There's no excuse for a nobody like you.
Holding power beyond your lowly station
will have you disgracing
yourself before you know it.
Tremendous power should be wielded by none
other than those with royal caliber, like me.
Though I pity you a little
for getting the wrong idea
after being deemed A-Class.
Screw you, Kirihara!
Laevateinn!
Yasu-kun!
Huh?
Why're you blowing your lid
and snapping on us?
So you're truly an irredeemable
nobody, Yasu Tomohiro?
Don't get it twisted
just because you're S-Class.
You're the one who needs
to take a hint, Kirihara Takuto!
There's still a hero who hasn't learned
a unique skill despite being S-Class,
even when all the other S-Class
heroes have theirs already.
See? Ayaka herself is proof.
And then there's Asagi,
who's learned a unique skill
- that surpasses Oyamada's at A-Class,
despite the fact that she's B-Class!
- Huh?!
that surpasses Oyamada's at A-Class,
despite the fact that she's B-Class!
You understand what I'm
trying to say, right?
In other words,
our hero rank isn't everything.
So assuming you're above us
just because you're S-Class...
is what a nobody getting
the wrong idea really looks like!
Eventually I'll show you which of us
is truly of royal caliber, you dumb bastard.
Why, you...
Stop it, Shougo.
Why?!
You're not gonna tell me you're
scared of him, are you?
Huh?
Oh, er, um... My bad.
Hmph. You're the nobodies.
I may be forced to admit
there's someone dragging down
the rest of us S-Class heroes.
You need to understand the
position you're in already, Sogou.
I guess I need to demonstrate my caliber
so that even you dense fools can grasp it.
I'm...
Asagi, I don't see the little pigeon.
What, really?
Well, she'll find her way back.
Yeah.
She's missing? Kashima-san's gone?
I'll go after Tooka.
Please tell me your reasoning.
There were too many monsters.
Even with his stat adjustments,
they're not everything.
More importantly,
Tooka's not in peak condition.
Ever since we hit the Land of Monsters,
he's gotten the least sleep of all of us.
I'm guessing he's been periodically
using "Sleep" on the rest of us,
all so we can slumber soundly
here in the Land of Monsters.
Sir Tooka has been sacrificing
his own rest since entering this land
in order to bolster our hope.
Thanks to that, we've managed
to make it to the heartland.
I wasn't just talking a big game
before we parted ways.
Hiding my presence and maneuvering
in this kind of terrain is my forte.
I also have night vision when it gets dark,
so I don't need to worry about a light
giving my position away.
I have sharp ears as ell.
I can tell those aren't baseless
lies to make me feel better.
Moreover...
if Tooka or Slei are badly wounded,
I'm the only one who can carry them.
We cannot afford to lose that man here.
I understand you're not acting
based on rash sentiments.
I thank you.
Forgive me.
With Sir Tooka absent,
I believe it's my duty to make decisions
for the safety of our group.
So I'm sorry for testing you like that.
You truly are fond of that man, aren't you?
Yes.
I have devoted myself to him, after all.
Big Sis?
Be sure you listen to Seras, okay?
Please take care of Sir Tooka.
I'm sorry, Lis.
Please promise me this.
Promise that you'll return alive.
Of course. I'm entrusting Lis to you, Seras.
I'll do whatever it takes to protect her.
Whatever it takes, huh?
Perhaps that's Tooka's
influence showing as well.
Okay, I'm heading out.
Wherever I fire, I'm bound to hit one of them.
So my first move...
is to spread out.
Do it!
Berserk!
That only scrambled them for a moment?
They switch gears too damn fast.
Choosing to kill over being killed...
Choosing to fight for survival...
Paralyze!
My surprise attack only stalled them
for a few seconds, buying me no time.
Also, the human-faced beasts in the front
that are adapting to my tentacle attacks
are still alive and well.
The stampede of monsters
lured you in too, huh?
Piggymaru, Slei!
Can you still keep going?
The rain's dampening sounds.
I can't follow them with just my ears now.
Can't say visibility's good either.
Status: Open.
TOOKA MIMORI
- Combining with Piggymaru
is essential to this battle.
However, at the rate things are going,
I can only keep this up ten more minutes.
To stay in the game, I'll have to level up.
The human-faced beasts are
worth a ton of EXP.
As long as I can keep killing them
and keep leveling up...
No, that's definitely too reckless.
Plus, if I'm not within a certain range,
then I don't get any EXP when they die.
That means I'll have to double back
the way we came.
If I say I've got this,
will you two follow me?
Truly...
I am truly blessed with allies.
Here we go!
Dark!
TOOKA MIMORI
Dark! Dark!
Paralyze! Paralyze!
Berserk!
Slei!
TOOKA MIMORI
We're there.
Welcome...
TOOKA MIMORI
into my range!
Berserk!
Now...
You have leveled up.
TOOKA MIMORI
- My MP's fully restored!
I can maintain combat!
Piggymaru!
I need to keep track of how far I can
earn EXP in this quasi-localized war.
It's the only way for us to fight and survive.
Paralyze! Berserk!
I have plenty of MP.
Now we just try to kill each other.
Two huge-ass monsters are on my tail.
Sleep!
My status ailment skill
requires me to have them in my line
of sight in order to affect them.
Behind you.
Paralyze!
Berserk! Berserk!
You have leveled up.
TOOKA MIMORI
Paralyze! Berserk!
Dark! Paralyze!
Par—!
Dark!
Paralyze!
Berserk!
Sleep!
Dark!
Berserk!
Paralyze!
Dark!
Sir Tooka!
You have leveled up.
- You have leveled up.
- Kill and slaughter, kill and slaughter...
Kill and slaughter, kill and slaughter...
I can't...
I know.
I'm not like Sogou-san.
All I could do was hide and watch when
they did that to Mimori-kun too.
Even so, I wanted to be useful.
I wanted to be able to care for others
even in awful moments like Sogou-san...
But I'm scared!
I'm going to die!
What's a human doing in a place like this?
They're similar.
THE ONE WHO CIRCULATES LIGHTNING
- Lightning Shifter, Unlock One.
UNLOCK STAGE ONE
Hey, you—
UNLOCK STAGE TWO
- Unlock Two.
Not only did you react to Stage One,
you withstood the damn blow...
But you can't escape my lightning now.
My throat... I can't speak...
Sorry.
On my sister's orders,
I can't let you kill Kashima.
Itsuki-san...
I see. These girls are...
Tooka told me about them.
They're the ones summoned by the goddess
to defeat the source of evil...
The heroes from another world!
RULER AND SWORD